So, absolutely, she's here. Thank you.
We'll talk to former Chief Andrew so as well.
Well, I can talk about Diana all day long and I won't.
So, very thankful, Diana's been a dispatcher in the police department for 25 years,
and within the last year, she's taken on the new role of being dispatch supervisor,
and she is doing an amazing job.
She brings her years of knowledge, her skill,
and she is just a very special person, a very special employee.
So, I'm very thankful that you're a coworker,
and we're really lucky to have you, so.
Okay.
If I could add on to, we are just getting started on budget.
And guess who got to go through the budget process first,
for the great first time to add.
And did a wonderful job.
And a lot of great ideas about where we can move ahead in the future
and this area too.
So, I want to just stand that as well.
Congratulations.
And I'd like to see if we'll have you able to go over.
Thank you.
Absolutely.
Thank you, man.
Thank you.
I have three public input.
I'm going to go to a personal present by Westergras the Council.
And I'll answer.
Now, we'll go to the item four.
Consented gender staffer.
It means that five, three, three, three, three,
three, three, two, three.
And be placed in the same gender.
Bye.
Thank you.
Second.
Westergras.
Aye.
Johnson.
Item four.
Team president.
Presentation of fiscal year 14, 15,
and all the day in the financial statement.
The same name for me as the authors.
Your book, Mr. Tyler?
Yes, sir.
You probably all have copies of this, or maybe like chronic copies, whichever.
Joe asked that we not make this a long meeting because you had a lot of other things.
You want to get out of here and get out real fast.
So we will do that with that one.
Probably the first thing we want to talk about is that on page five,
and then on page 97 to 100 is our reports.
And basically, probably good news is we have no harder exceptions.
So that these are standard opinions and nothing unusual.
Then on maybe on page eight, if you're looking at that one,
there's our financial highlights.
And I want to do that because that is what's happened to us the past year.
You see that we increase in that position.
Excess revenue over expenditures are over two million dollars. I mean, that's that's something to be said for us as far as the city's concerned
The
It says on that second bullet there says during the year of the cities expenses for a government like to have these were 12.8 million
And those were funded with 1.4 million of program revenues and 7.4 million of
general revenues and then we actually transferred from
MSU a other 5.2 million to cover us in the city's business high activities
Which includes utilities of course
Program revenues exceed expenses by 6.1 million and again, that's that's the item that let us transfer that 5.2 million over to
subsidized the general government
Next we'll write in their talks about the general fund
had unsigned fund balance of only 235,000 a year in the rest of it was
restricted money and whatnot
And that last bullet there talks about the
the budget numbers
You're talking about doing budget for this year last year our final budget wound up being about
2.10 7% below what we anticipated revenue to be there were that much less
But on the good side of that
expenditures were about 21% less and all we thought we could or all we was able to spend so we kept spending down and revenue broke about what we thought it would
The other thing maybe everyone run through is over if you look at
page 12 there under
The government activities you can see that we were showing the increase of roughly
a
million to 70 that's the difference between last year and this year and this
Management discussion in analysis one of the few places where it does compare last year to this year most of the rest of the out of report is just showing
this year's
activities
But here you can see that we did increase our net position by million two on the government activities and about 900,000 on
the
Business type of utility activities for total of roughly 2,000,000,000,000,000
But then if you look over on page 13 there's the very bottom again. It's kind of a recap of
Revenue and expenses, but you can see there at the bottom it says that the government activities were
Actually short about 3.9 million there and we transferred in 5. I was 5.2 to cover that from the
You totally side we've got us to an excess with me in 2 and then on the business side they were actually
almost 6.1 over in revenue and we transfer that 5.2 out of the air to get us about 900,000
net at the end of the year for them. So again, I'll say, your manager did a great job for this year
as far as I'm concerned. I mean the numbers just make it look, you know, that we just did a real
super job. Not your manager, your staff, did a great job. Manager and staff did a super job.
So there's a lot to this report and we could talk about it for an hour for one or two, but
there's no need to, because I say, bottom line is that we really had a good year and a lot
better than some of the smaller towns that I'd deal with that are continually fighting the revenue
problem that we're just in really good shape this year. Maybe I have some questions I should be
Can we get his contact information and get Meyer one of these?
I don't want him to spot him. I don't want him to spot him. I don't want him to spot him.
I mean, I mean, I mean, copies came for everybody I know. And at the same time, you know, if the
Meyer would want to come back, it's that when we'd come back at some point in time to talk about this,
I'm glad to do that too. So because that's the you guys. How does the second most important
financial document we do other than the budget? It looks true. It wants us to get back together
or something like that. We're more than happy to do that. We know this is kind of abbreviated meeting,
but we can spend a lot of time going on if you'd like. Yeah, you really can. And the other really good news,
this is the top line that, you know, I've been doing this out of for you guys for about four or five years now.
And we finally, this is our first year that we're going to be able to file with federal clearinghouse,
like we're supposed to. You don't federal programs, which puts our name in a pile on the list of
being able to get federal programming that we've been able to do this first time since that time here.
You know, we were way behind when I first started with you guys. And in now we, this March 31st,
our due date on that, we'll get it sent in to them and had that too. We're finally on the good side of
that. And that's one of the reasons why we needed to have it on your, that's such a special meeting for
night. I'm sure you said. We'd like a couple of years behind. We were two years back. We started
and it's right. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. I'm 15. I don't think the normal round will
be understanding with North East Oklahoma Soccer Association for Spring League at the same
world soccer complex. James, I guess that to you, man, it's probably going to pour it or something.
So, this is the, you know, it's kind of like what we did at the high school for the jump
public field. And the MOU's just showing responsibility between the Soccer Association and us.
We also, I do know, we got the other leagues and we're planning on doing that with them too.
And it'll be on the next council. We got a doll, softball, a little league baseball, and then the
girl, softball. Just a soccer field, soccer season.
started off around and do this. But again, getting our house in order, this is something we really
need to do. And this is really one of the first steps toward what we've discussed with about
and we'll talk about it in the budget with kind of the sports authority in trying to help out
with these organizations. So originally Amanda was going to be here, but she's leaving on a
Columbus city, but in an opti-distant future, we'll probably have a much deeper detailed discussion
about where we stand on that. So this is really the top of her step and they're going to take
and toward a lot of other things coming up. Yeah, it's going to be busy, I believe. Yeah, it's very
much so. Thank you, Jane. Thank you. I'm 16. I need an extra on that. Oh, we go. Yes, okay. Yes. Motion to
prove. I'll make a motion. I'll second. Forster. All right. Western. I. Johnson. All right. I'm 16. I need
a bit of this thing. No, not on this agenda. I'm 17 step reports. Jim, have anything? Joe,
do you want to add anything to this? Well, thank you. I don't want to add anything to this.
I don't want to add anything to this. Nothing. Nothing. Nothing on my mind.
I've got three very quick things. I'll leave very, very quick on. I've never one is just a reminder
of the community cleanup is taking place. So we have all the information about the details in our
on a website of people listening in. I see a lot of stuff at the curb side. I think a lot of people
are catching on. I'm happy about that. Secondly, very, very good news. We have been working with FEMA in
regards to the flood mapping that we've been discussing. And we've had a preliminary discussion with FEMA
and they are taking a very strong look at the tetrax study that we had done. And in essence,
what they're doing is they are suspending this process at this point so they can look at the tetrax study
because simply put, they didn't have the information that we had through tetrax. And the information is showing
that the flood maps do not have to be as high as they are originally looking at. So they're going to be
taking a look at that. We hope that they're going to be reduced significantly over the five feet that we thought
we were going to be having. Probably in about two weeks will have another conference call with them. We'll
keep you in touch. But right now we're developing a very good in relationship with FEMA
in regards to the fact that we've done our homework. So I want to compliment everybody that was involved
and the council for approving the tetrax study. If this alone reduces everything back to where we're
at before, maybe just a slight increase, the study's already paid for itself. So I think that's incredibly
good news. And then Neil, I don't know. You might want to talk about where we're at with the animal shelter.
Yeah, last I heard anyway was the bucket coming with him budget, pretty close. So we're hoping
two months or basically moving full speed ahead I think we'll have an item on your
agenda on the fifth. Nothing has changed as a go. No, okay. That's good news. I
thought you'd like to say that. Yeah, that's it. Okay.
Good. Good way of the German. I think it's time.
I hope you're the German. Second question. Hi.
Four-ster.
Johnson.
Hi.
Thank you.
Hey, Joe.
Good afternoon.